杰森:【歌唱】美好的一天!!阳光普照,照我还家!美好的一天!我要倾诉,诉我衷肠!【继续歌唱】谢谢!谢谢!谢谢你!谢谢午餐牛排!
Jason: Day-Oh!Daay-Oh!Daylight come and me want to go home.Day!Me
say Day!Me say Day![Continues singing] Oh, oh!Well, thank you, thank you.I
thank you and my meat thanks you
开萝尔:幸亏没把我朋友带回家!
Carol: I just thank God I didn't bring home any of my friends.
麦琪:我也是!
Maggie: Oh, me too.
杰森:本!
Jason: Ben!
本:爸爸,我根本没有为此而难堪!
Ben: I'm not ashamed of you at all, Dad.
杰森:谢谢!
Jason: Thank you!
本:混蛋萨利文的爸爸能用胳肢窝奏出国歌.对了,
Ben: Stinky Sullivan's dad plays the Star-Spangled Banner on his armpit.
妈妈今天下午你怎么看怎么漂亮.
And Mom you're looking especially lovely this afternoon.
麦琪:真的,谢谢,本杰明.
Maggie: Why, thank you, Benjamin.
本:本公子生而有幸,得遇貌若天仙的母亲,
Ben: Boy, what a lucky guy I am to have such a beautiful Mom and a
歌喉婉转圆润的父亲.
musical Dad.
杰森:嗯,我们应该感到高兴才是,
Jason: Well, I think we're the lucky parents Ben because we have a son
麦琪,
who says such nice things about us and not only because he's trying to
我们的乖儿子能如此奉承咱俩,不过你觉得他这样是不是有所求?
butter us up or something, but just because he cares, right?
本:爸爸妈妈你们等会,我去去就来.
Ben: Excuse me a minute.Don't go away.
杰森:接下来他会讲些什么?
Jason: What would you like to hear next?
本:迈克,爸妈不吃这套.
Ben: Mike, your scam didn't work.
迈克:怎么就不管用呢?
Mike: How could it not work?
本:我还没开始大讲特讲好话呢,爸爸就发觉了我的意图,
Ben: I didn't even get to finish the buttering up stuff.
还对我挤眉弄眼!
Dad caught me off with one of those looks of his where he squints his eyes.
迈克:想买辆新自行车的事你真的题也没提?
Mike: Are you sure you didn't mention anything about wanting a new bike?
本:当然.现在该怎么办?
Ben: No.I never got that far.What'll I do now?
迈克:嗯,那你帮我擦车,我替你想想办法.
Mike: Well, you buff that fender while I think.
本:不管怎样,我都得让爸妈把那辆自行车买回来!
Ben: Anything, Mike.I gotta have that bike!Got to!Got to!Got to!
天好冷啊!
It's so cool!
迈克:好啦!好啦!运动运动就暖和了.嗨,这块你怎么没擦.
Mike: Ok, ok.Alright, just take it easy.You missed a spot there.
本:对不起.
Ben: Oh, sorry.
迈克:够了!看看你擦的这个车.
Mike: Alright, just watch what you're doing.
这样吧,你给爸妈说这事的时候首先要诚恳一点.
Ok, now the first thing we got to work on is the sincerity of your delivery.
本:诚恳?
Ben: Sincerity?
迈克:那当然,诚恳是父母判断自己孩子的首要标准,
Mike: Yea, see, sincerity is the most important thing parents look for
做不到你就什么也甭想了.
in their kids.If you can't fake that, you're dead meat.
本:啊噢!
Ben: Uh huh.
迈克:本,用点力擦行不行?
Mike: Ben, you got to rub harder than that, alright?
你要是连汽车都不会擦,那我怎么教你更难的事情呢?
How can I teach something that complicated if you can't even buff my car?
本:噢!我会擦车,我当然会,
Ben: Oh, I can.I can!I'll prove it.Mike, you got to help me!
不信我证明给你看.迈克你一定要帮我!
You're so slick, you could con people into doing anything,
你鬼点子最多,能让别人做任何他们本人都不愿意干的事,最后就连他们也莫明其妙.
even if they don't want to, and they don't even know it!
迈克:别忘了好好擦擦挡板.
Mike: Don't forget the chrome.
本:收到!!!!
Ben: AAAAAA!!!!
杰森:本,刚才我们说到哪了?
Jason: So, Ben, where were we?
本:嗯?
Ben: Huh?
杰森:你刚才把我们说得天花乱坠,可刚开始你就出去了,
Jason: Well, you were telling us what great parents we were and then you
想起来没?
said, oh excuse me a minute and you left.
本:算了,不想说了.
Ben: Oh, yea.Forget it.
麦琪:嗯!可我倒想跟你说说,
Maggie: Well, I want to talk to you about all this screaming business.
刚才大喊大叫的,到底为了什么,这可不大像话.
You're getting far too old for it.
本:那好,你先告诉迈克离我远点!
Ben: Then tell Mike to keep away from me.
麦琪:迈克怎么招你了?
Maggie: What did Mike do?
本:他说得好好的要帮我,
Ben: Well, he acted like he was gonna help me,
结果只是想让我替他擦那辆破车.
but all he wanted me to do was wax his stupid car.
麦琪:帮你做什么?
Maggie: Help you do what?
本:他说会教我怎么让你们替我买辆新……不好意思,
Ben: He was showing me how to get you guys to buy me a new Um,
我去一下洗手间.
excuse me a minute.I got to go to the bathroom or something.
开萝尔:本,心情不好的话找我聊聊.到底怎么了?
Carol: Ben, can't you go sulk in your own room?Ok, ok, what is it?
本:最近新出了一种新型自行车,
Ben: Well, see, there's this really rad new bike called The Sidewalk Screamer
我很想买一辆.
and I just got to have it,
但要是让爸爸妈妈给我买的话,他们就会说我已经有一辆了,
but I know if I ask Mom or Dad for it,
可那辆车已经骑了那么长时间,
they'll say I already got a bike.Even though it's old and pukey.
破的都快没样了.
So I went to Mike for advice.
所以我就找迈克帮忙,
And he told me this really neat way to ask them for it and when I
他就教我如何如何,结果却不灵.
tried it, it didn't work.
后来我又去找他,
So, I went back to Mike and all he did was con me into waxing his
可他让我替他擦车.
car.
开萝尔:你找迈克帮忙?
Carol: You went to Mike for help?
本:不对吗?
Ben: What's wrong with that?
开萝尔:他是个不折不扣的小滑头,你还不知道.
Carol: He's a slime ball.
本:嘿!他以诡计多端着称,懂的不少.
Ben: Hey, he's the neatest guy on Earth and he knows everything!
开萝尔:我还以为你生他的气呢.
Carol: I thought you were mad at him!
本:照理我对他这么好,他应该好好帮我才是,却不知怎么对我这样?
Ben: Oh, yea.I like him so much, how come he treats me like this?
迈克:本,我刚才突然为你想到了怎么才能把那辆自行车弄到手的办法.
Mike: Hey, Ben, I figured out the perfect way for you to get that new bike.
本:真的?那你快点讲啊.
Ben: Yea, really, what?
迈克:但是你得帮我擦车.
Mike: And I just may tell you if you come finish that wax job.
本:果然是个大滑头.
Ben: What a slime ball.
开萝尔:你去哪?
Carol: Where are you going?
本:开萝尔,你说我该怎么办?
Ben: Carol, I don't have a choice.
开萝尔:别担心,会有办法!
Carol: Ben, sure you do!Now come on!Don't let him do this to you!
你又去让他利用.
It's sheer folly.
本:不找他找谁呢?
Ben: Carol, if Mike doesn't help me, who will?
开萝尔:我帮你.
Carol: I will.
本:就你?你一个女的知道什么呀?
Ben: You?What do you know?You're a girl.
开萝尔:幸亏碰上了我,
Carol: I've gotten to you just in time.
要不然又得给迈克擦车.
Ben, you know, Mike is not the only one in this family who knows how to
本,家里不是只有迈克才知道怎么跟爸爸妈妈斗心眼.
deal with Mom and Dad.
在家有谁在可以想什么时候睡觉就什么时候?
Who in this house can stay up as late as she wants?
本:妈妈.
Ben: Mom.
开萝尔:是我!本!
Carol: Me, Ben, me!
是我!我可以一个人去上晚自习,可也从没受过处罚.
And I can go out on a school night and I never, ever get punished.
本:那是因为你表现好,开萝尔!我可不行!.
Ben: That's because you're perfect, Carol.I can't use that, they're on to me.
开萝尔:不说这个了!要是不想听我的,那就去给迈克擦车吧!
Carol: Well, fine, then.Fine.Just go get taken by Mike, ok?
本:那你有什么好办法?
Ben: Ok, what do you got?
本:妈妈!爸爸!我得向你们坦白一件事.
Ben: Mom, Dad, I have a confession to make.
麦琪:怎么啦?
Maggie: Oh?
本:你们还记不记得,我说你美丽,
Ben: Well, you remember how I told you,
说爸爸懂音乐,都是假的.
you were beautiful and you were musical?I was lying.
我有事情求你们,才说好听的让你们听的!
I was just buttering you up to ask you for something.Sheer folly.
杰森:全是骗人的?
Jason: Sheer folly?
麦琪:坐下,本.
Maggie: Sit down, Ben.
本:我想买一辆新自行车,
Ben: I just wanted to apologize for getting so excited about this great
所以才这样的!
new bike that even Chris Kusman's dad got him.
我看见克里斯·库斯曼的爸爸都给他买了一辆.我也不知道自己怎么就这么做,
Sometimes I don't know what gets into me.
也许是跟迈克学的.
I probably been hanging around Mike too much.
麦琪:宝贝,要是你进来就直接跟我们说想要自行车,
Maggie: Honey, if you'd just come in here and told us that you wanted
我们就会给你买的.
a new bike, we would've.
杰森:晕!!!没事,开开玩笑而已!
Jason: Fainted.I'm kidding about fainting.Sorta kidding.
麦琪:这车多少钱.
Maggie: How much is this bike?
本:120美元.
Ben: $120.
杰森:120美元买辆自行车?!
Jason: For a bike?!
本:我现在想问问你们,要是我自己想法把钱攒够,
Ben: Well, what I'd really like to know is if I were to work real hard
你们同不同意让我去买?
and save every penny, would I have your permission to buy that bike myself?
麦琪:那当然,小南瓜.
Maggie: Why, of course, pumpkin.
杰森:绝对同意,我还以为你要我们替你买呢.
Jason: Absolutely.We thought you meant for us to buy it for you.
本:谢谢妈妈.
Ben: Thanks, Mom.
麦琪:宝贝,要是你自己能攒到一半,
Maggie: And honey if you can manage to save half of that, $60,
60美元,另一半就由我们来付.
we'll pay for the other half.
本:你们付?
Ben: You will?
杰森:我们付?
Jason: We will?
迈克:嘿!本!本!?
Mike: Hey, Ben!Ben!
开萝尔:他忙着呢.
Carol: He's busy!
迈克:最好别这样!
Mike: Well, he better not be.
车刚打上蜡,
That wax starts to harden,
他现在应该给车抛光.
he's gonna have one heck of a time getting a decent shine.
开萝尔:本又不是你仆人.
Carol: Ben is not your personal lackey.
迈克:哦?
Mike: Oh?
开萝尔:仆人的意思你知道吗?
Carol: Do you know what lackey means?
迈克:那当然!那你说说你的看法.
Mike: Of course, let's hear what you think it means.
开萝尔:就是奴隶.
Carol: Slave.
迈克:我也这么想.
Mike: Hey, that's pretty close to my definition.
开萝尔:那当然!
Carol: Yea, Right.
迈克:现在告诉你,我可没把本当作我得奴隶,
Mike: And for your information I don't think of Ben as my slave.
我们是互相帮助,
We just help each other out.
各取所需!这是最可宝贵的兄弟情谊.
It's part of a brother bonding thing that is very beautiful.
本:开萝尔!开萝尔!你的办法一试就灵.
Ben: Carol!Carol!It worked perfect!
开萝尔:看,没错吧!
Carol: Oh, I told you it would!
迈克:你在说什么?什么办法一试就灵?
Mike: What?What worked perfect?
本:爸妈说什么都被你猜到了.
Ben: They said everything you said they would.
迈克:怎么回事?
Mike: Hey, what's going on?
开萝尔:那就好,继续执行我的计划.
Carol: Ok, here's the rest of my plan.
迈克:你们的事我根本没兴趣,
Mike: You know, I don't even care what you guys are saying,
我是想帮忙才过来的.
I'm just listening out of kindness here.
本:开萝尔,全都服从你的安排.
Ben: Whatever you say, Carol.
开萝尔:好,听着.
Carol: Alright.Here's
迈克:嘿!当我不存在?!
Mike: Hey!
本:嗨,迈克.
Ben: Oh, hi Mike.
迈克:刚才不是说好了吗,你帮我擦车,
Mike: Come on, I thought you were going to help me with my car and I
我帮你弄到自行车.
was going to help you with your bike.
本:现在不用你帮忙,迈克.
Ben: I don't need your help, Mike.
迈克:不用我帮忙?
Mike: Oh, no?
开萝尔:没错,我代劳.
Carol: No, I helped Ben.
本:她的办法比你的好多了,肯定奏效!
Ben: She sure did!And it wasn't like your plan, Mike.It worked.
称得上立竿见影!开萝尔,
Mom and Dad are going to come up with half the money,
你说得没错,爸爸妈妈答应一半的钱.
just like you said they would.
迈克:出一半钱,出一半,
Mike: Half of it?Half of it?Ha!
那你得拼死拼活干多少天才攒齐60块,果然是个好办法,
Oh, so now all's you gotta do is bust your tail to earn sixty bucks and
好主意,开萝尔!
you're home free.Good plan, great thinking there, Carol.
本:噢!对了,你还没告诉我这60块钱该怎么去挣呢.
Ben: Oh, no, you never told me how I'm supposed to make the $60.
开萝尔:本,你听我说.
Carol: Ben, listen to me.
迈克:他听你讲的已经够多的了,
Mike: No, I think he's listened to you just about enough.
你要真想那辆车,给我擦车我就给你好好想个主意,
Now if you really want this bike,
怎么样?
I have some thoughts we can discuss while we buff the car, Ben, buddy.
本:真的啊?
Ben: Really, buddy?
开萝尔:你不用做任何事就能挣到60美元,本!
Carol: You don't need to earn the $60, Ben.
本:那还是你自己去擦吧.
Ben: Buff your own stinking car, Mike.
开萝尔:好了,
Carol: Ok, now for the second part of my plan.
我们按计划实施第二步行动.
You think any of your friends would be willing to pay,
你能不能找个愿意出一块钱买你的旧车的朋友.
say, $1 for your old bike?
本:当然啦,这样的好事谁不愿意?.
Ben: Heck, yea!Who wouldn't?
开萝尔:那好,所以你只要想办法卖掉60张一块钱的彩票,
Carol: Alright, then all you have to do is sell sixty raffle tickets for
谁中彩就把那车拿走.
a dollar a piece and the winner gets your old bike.
本:哇噢!.
Ben: Wow!
迈克:浪费时间!
Mike: Hey, what a great waste of time.
开萝尔:你究竟明不明白这个计划,迈克!
Carol: Uh, what part of my plan was too complicated for you, Mike?
别理他,我们按计划行事,本!.
Let's work out the details, Benny.
本:好,我听你的安排,开萝尔.
Ben: I'm with you, Carol.
迈克:这个计划根本行不通.本!
Mike: This plan is doomed, Ben.
这种赌博性质的卖彩票,只有慈善机构才可以搞,
And only because it's illegal to run a gambling operation in this state
其他人这么做是违法的!等着瞧吧,等着开萝尔的伟大计划一失败,
if you're not a nun or a priest.Oh, fine, then.Go ahead and ignore me.
你就会趴在地上来求我,听到没,
But when Carol's brilliant idea fails, which it will,
本,本?
I know you'll come crawling back to me, Ben.Ben?
电视节目:本月每晚,我台将播出一部关于南北战争葛底斯堡战役的历史剧,讲的是手足兄弟间的互相残杀.
TV: Tonight and every night this month,
the longest mini-series in the history of television.
Set against the sprawling Civil War battlefield of Gettysburg,
brother pitted against brother
迈克:我打赌肯定是她们姐妹引起的.
Mike: I bet their sister started it.
杰森:真是太可笑了!我在医学院饱读诗书,现在却要打扫厨房.
Jason: Oh, it's amazing, isn't it?After all those years of medical school your dad is still out there cleaning the kitchen.
迈克:今晚还没轮到我洗碗筷,轮到开萝尔,那边就是值日表,不信你自己去看.
Mike: Now, Dad, it is not my night to do the dishes.It's Carol's, I can prove it.I have a list.
杰森:别担心,迈克!本已经洗完了.
Jason: Relax, Mike.Ben already did the dishes.
迈克:替开萝尔做的!理应如此.
Mike: Yea, for Carol.It figures.
麦琪:迈克,今晚该你倒垃圾.
Maggie: Michael, your night to take out the trash.
迈克:我就去,妈妈.
Mike: Oh, just perfect, Mom.
麦琪:他们俩呢?
Maggie: Where's your brother and sister?
迈克:在楼上大闹天宫呢.
Mike: Oh, upstairs, laughing, joking, talking, sharing.
杰森:我去叫他们下来干活.
Jason: Well, I can certainly put a stop to that.
麦琪:有事吗,迈克?
Maggie: Something wrong, Mike?
迈克:没事,说了你们也步明白.
Mike: No, nothing you guys can understand.
杰森:那你到说来听听.
Jason: Try us.
迈克:好吧,能不能想象有这么一个孩子,
Mike: Do you have any idea what it's like showing the kid the ropes,
他从小是你带大的,
teaching him how to get by, raising the kid from birth, and then,
而且他什么都听你的,
just one day, all of a sudden, you lose control.
突然有一天他什么也不听你的了,而且连一句话也不听你的了.
Suddenly he just doesn't listen to a word you say!
杰森:嗯,我的确什么都没听明白!麦琪你明白点什么没?
Jason: Well, I don't have a clue.How about you, Maggie?
迈克:班尼!本!
Mike: Benny!Hey, Ben!
我带你出去逛逛,顺便把垃圾倒掉!
I thought we could shoot a few hoops, maybe get some ice cream,
怎么样,本?
take out the trash.Hey, Ben!
开萝尔:别动,本!,不然我揍你.
Carol: Don't move, Ben, or I'll stick you.
本:不,不不不不.
Ben: Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
开萝尔:嗨,迈克!.
Carol: Hi, Mike!Ben, don't move!
别动,我花那么大力气帮你搞彩票,
I mean, with all the help I'm giving you on this raffle,
你帮我做这么点小事情,又算得了什么?
it does not hurt you to help me with a little chore of mine.
迈克:明白……
Mike: Uhh...
开萝尔:迈克,我们忙着呢!请你先出去.
Carol: Mike, we're busy.Get out.
迈克:爸爸妈妈让我来找你,
Mike: Look, Mom and Dad sent me up here to get you.
他们说今天轮到你倒垃圾.
They said it's your turn to take out the trash.
开萝尔:不是我,今天该轮到我洗盘子,
Carol: It is not.It was my turn to do the dishes.
这一点我已经做到了.
which I have taken care of.
迈克:反正是他们让我来找你的.好吧,
Mike: Look, All's I know is they said for you to do it.Alright.
别动Ben,折臂还没做好呢.
Don't move, Ben.I'm not done with that half.
本:瞧着我干嘛.
Ben: Stop looking at me!
迈克:没办法,你太聪明了.
Mike: What?I can't help it.You look cute.
本:滚一边去!
Ben: Leave me alone, Mike.
迈克:本,我是来救你的.
Mike: Hey, Benny, I'm just here to save you!
本:用不着.
Ben: I'm fine.
迈克:用不着?本,
Mike: You're fine?Ben, don't you see what's happening here?
你倒看看你在干什么,你现在没法去吃冰激凌,
I mean, you pass up a chance to shoot a few hoops,
没法去玩射击,却在这当衣架.
maybe pig out on some ice cream so you can stand here in this dress?
本:服装设计!!.
Ben: It's a gown!
迈克:这有意思吗?.本,
Mike: So, that makes it ok?Ben, look, don't you see what's happening?
你自个看看你这是怎么回事,你彻底成了开萝尔的仆人.
Look you're becoming Carol's lackey.
本:什么意思?
Ben: What's that?
迈克:你不知道那是什么意思?你去哪?
Mike: You don't know what lackey means?Where you been?
本:当衣架,行了吧?仆人是什么意思?
Ben: In a gown, ok?What's it mean?
迈克:走狗,奴才,奴隶.
Mike: Toady, grunt, slave.
本:你意思就是开萝尔像你那样对我.
Ben: Oh, you mean like what you use me for.
迈克:本,得了吧!
Mike: Ben, are you kidding?
我让你干过这事没?
I mean have I ever once asked you to wear a dress?
本:那倒没有!
Ben: No.I would've.
迈克:本,你瞧瞧你那副德行,还美呢.
Mike: Ben, come on, man.Don't you see what she's doing to you?
本:迈克,你爱怎么着就怎么着,反正开萝尔能让我得到那辆自行车.
Ben: Mike you can say anything you want, but Carol's getting me a bike.
迈克:男车还是女车?
Mike: Uh huh.Boy's bike or girl's?
开萝尔:回见妈妈!回见爸爸!
Carol: Bye Mom!Bye Dad!Have a fun time shopping!
你们放心,我会管好本.
Take your time, I'll keep my eye on Ben and what's his name.
迈克:开萝尔,过来陪我练球.
Mike: Carol, come on!I'm dribbling here!
开萝尔:离我远点.
Carol: So use your sleeve.
迈克:你卖彩票自以为做的很聪明,
Mike: Oh, you think you're real slick with this raffle thing, don't you?
你骗得了本这个小笨蛋,能逃得过我的法眼!
But you can just kid yourself that you're doing all this for little Ben.
开萝尔,
But you don't fool me, Carol.
我肚子里很清楚,你这种假仁假义的做法,
I know you're just doing this because, for once in your pathetic life,
完全是为了出我的洋相.
you see a chance to top me.
开萝尔:抱歉,你在跟我讲话吗?
Carol: Oh, sorry, Mike.Were you speaking to me?
迈克:你这样利用本也太残酷了.
Mike: You know, I think it's really cruel the way you're using Ben.
开萝尔:对,你就放心吧,
Carol: Yea, well, I guess I don't have as much experience in using people
我可不会像你那样,满脑袋就想着怎么利用别人.
as you do.
迈克:很对,不.
Mike: That's right.I mean, no.
乔迪:你瞧瞧,本你把事情全搞砸了,
Jody: Face it, Ben you blew it.I told you, you were gonna mess up.
我说过不能这样,可是你就是不听.
But did you listen?
开萝尔:乔迪,怎么回事?本怎么了?
Carol: What happened?Jody what did he do?
乔迪:事情全给这小子搞糟了.
Jody: He just ruined the whole raffle, that's all.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?!
乔迪:头两张彩票他卖给了波波茨兄弟.
Jody: He sold the first two tickets to the Bobotz brothers.
开萝尔:然后呢?
Carol: So?
本:他们兄弟俩放话说,谁要是再敢买彩票,
Ben: So they put the word out if anybody else buys a ticket,
他们就扁谁.
they'll pound them.
开萝尔:就是说,现在为止你一共才卖掉了两张彩票.
Carol: So you only sold two tickets?
乔迪:不是,我也买了一张,我才不怕他们兄弟俩呢.
Jody: No, I bought one, too.The Bobotz's don't scare me.
迈克:等等,你的旧自行车就卖了三美元.
Mike: So, wait a minute, you're selling your bike for $3?
乔迪:两块五,他给我打了五折.
Jody: $2.50, I got a discount.
本:开萝尔,该怎么办,该怎么办!!
Ben: Carol, what will I do?What will I do?
迈克:是啊,开萝尔,你的伟大彩票计划可不能泡汤,哈哈我看你该怎么办!!
Mike: Yes, Carol, what's the next step in your Can't Lose Raffle scheme?
开萝尔:不可能!绝对不可能!
Carol: This is impossible!I mean, totally and completely.
所有可能性我都考虑过了.
I calculated all the probabilities.
本:是啊!
Ben: Yea, right.
迈克:本,现在只有我能救你了!!
Mike: I'd be glad to help you, Ben.
本:你能救我!?谢谢!谢谢!谢谢!!
Ben: You will?Thank you!Thank you!Thank you!
迈克:不过你得先把开萝尔赶走.
Mike: But first thing we got to do is get rid of Carol.
本:开萝尔?
Ben: Carol who?
迈克:本!!
Mike: Ben!
本:开萝尔,你还是哪凉快就去哪凉快吧?
Ben: You're history, Carol.
杰森:嗨!孩子们.
Jason: Hi kids.
本和开萝尔:爸爸妈妈好.
Ben and Carol: Hi.
开萝尔:妈妈!爸爸!
Carol: Mom!Dad!
本:噢!别这样!
Ben: Oh, no!
乔迪:这下可热闹了.
Jody: This is getting good.
开萝尔:我还以为你们去购物了呢.
Carol: I thought you two went shopping.
麦琪:我们是去购物了,可我们又转回来了.
Maggie: That's what you were supposed to think.We parked around the corner.
杰森:你们以为你们的爸爸就会傻乎乎的唱唱那种傻歌,我知道你们准有事.
Jason: What do you think?
We just hang around the kitchen all day playing calypso songs on meat?
We know when something's up.
麦琪:我们知道.
Maggie: Oh, we sure do.
杰森:怎么回事?一块钱一辆自行车?本?
Jason: So, what is it?Win a bike for a buck?!Ben?
迈克:得了,还是实话实说.
Mike: Well, here I think we should just tell them the truth.
本:呃?
Ben: Huh?
杰森:对,从实招来.
Jason: Yea, give that a shot.
迈克:好吧,我来讲,
Mike: Well, uh, the truth is that, um,
是这么回事,本想用卖彩票的办法,
little Ben here was raffling off his old bike to raise his half of the
把旧车卖掉,然后用这笔钱来买新车.
money for the new bike.
杰森:本,我们是要你打工挣钱.
Jason: Ben, we expected you to earn that money.
迈克:对,是该这样.
Mike: Hey, we all did.
他现在已经知道这样子是不对的了,是这样吗?本.
But I think the little guy here knows that what he did was wrong.Right, Ben?
本:迈克!
Ben: Mike!
迈克:这种做法是应该受到惩罚的.
Mike: But this should certainly not go unpunished.
本:不会吧?
Ben: What?
迈克:我认为你们做父母的,应该做的第一件事,
Mike: I think that a fitting punishment is for you two fine parents to
就是马上取消摸彩票,
just call this whole raffle thing off and you should tell any kid that
然后你们应该告诉买彩票的人,
comes up here that Ben is not raffling off his old bike and, uh,
那辆自行车不卖了,最后把钱退还给他们.
you should give them the money back.
本:是的,我错了,是我做的,罚我吧.
Ben: Yes, I'm guilty.I did it.Punish me.
麦琪:迈克还是本?
Maggie: You want Mike or Ben?
杰森:都是迈克干得好事.
Jason: I took Mike last time.
麦琪:迈克,你过来.
Maggie: Mike come with me.
迈克:什么?妈妈,我只是个无辜的旁观者.
Mike: What?Mom, I'm an innocent bystander here.
麦琪:不会吧?
Maggie: Sure.
迈克:我是无辜的.开萝尔你倒是说句话啊?!
Mike: I am.Carol would you say something?
开萝尔:我得去学习了.
Carol: I have a lot of studying to do.
迈克:开萝尔!
Mike: Carol!
麦琪:迈克,你就老老实实迪招了吧!.
Maggie: Mike, I'm waiting.
杰森:你妈在等你说话呢,迈克!.
Jason: She's waiting, Mike.
迈克:我算是明白了,
Mike: Oh, fine, fine.
家里不管出了什么坏事,
But why is it that every time something goes wrong in this house,
你们总是以为我干的!!.
I'm always the one that gets blamed for it?
杰森:一共有几个人买了你的彩票?
Jason: How many kids do you have to pay back?
本:三个.
Ben: Three.
杰森:你这辆自行车才卖了三美元?
Jason: You were gonna raffle your bike for three bucks?
乔迪:两块五,本给我打了五折.
Jody: Two-fifty.I got a discount.
麦琪:迈克,你以为这件事能遮掩过去?
Maggie: Mike, how many times do we have to cover this?
本可是对你崇拜得一塌糊涂.
You know Ben worships you.
不管什么,
You know he'll follow your lead no matter how stupid or scatter-brained
只要是你带的头,他还不是你的跟屁虫.
your idea is.
迈克:妈妈!
Mike: Mom.
麦琪:别跟我装模作样的小伙子.卖彩票是违法的,
Maggie: Don't you take that tone with me, young man.Raffles are illegal.
你弟弟也许会被警察抓起来.
You could've gotten our little Ben thrown in the slammer!
迈克:妈妈,首先,我同意这个主意的确坏的不能再坏了.
Mike: Mom, first of all, I agree.It was an incredibly stupid idea.
麦琪:坦白从宽,继续说.
Maggie: Oh, progress.
迈克:可这跟我无关.
Mike: But the idea wasn't mine.
麦琪:噢,行了!
Maggie: Oh, come on Mike.
迈克,本再聪明也想不出卖彩票这个鬼主意.
Ben isn't sophisticated enough to come up with something like this on his own.
迈克:我知道.
Mike: I know.
麦琪:那这是谁的主意.
Maggie: Then whose idea was it?
迈克:开萝尔.
Mike: Carol's.
麦琪:哈!开萝尔·西维尔?
Maggie: Ha!Carol Seaver?
迈克:没错,就是她.
Mike: Yes.
开萝尔:妈妈,我要去黛比家.
Carol: Mom, I'm going over to Debbie's.I'll probably stay for dinner.
我可能要在她家吃完饭,也可能今晚不回来了.
In fact, there's a good chance I'll stay overnight.
麦琪:再见亲爱的.
Maggie: Bye sweetheart.
迈克:她要溜了!!.
Mike: She's getting away!
麦琪:迈克,你越不老实,就越要重重惩罚你.
Maggie: Mike you are only making things worse for yourself.
迈克:妈妈,别误会我!是我一直在劝他们别去卖彩票.
Mike: Mom, I tried to talk Ben and Carol out of this all along.
麦琪:你以为我真的会相信,
Maggie: So you expect me to believe that it was Carol's idea that Ben
是开萝尔为本出了这么个馊主意,让他去卖彩票,
have an illegal raffle and the whole time you were the voice of reason
而你倒在一旁劝他们.
as you tried desperately to convince them that what they were doing was wrong?
迈克:那你只能去找我的律师了.
Mike: I believe I have the right to an attorney.
杰森:本,那辆自行车花了75美元.
Jason: Ben, that bike cost us seventy-five bucks.
波波茨兄弟之一:西维尔家的心肝宝贝,波波茨兄弟领车来了.
Bobotz brother 1: Ok, Seaver head.The Bobotz boys are here.
波波茨兄弟之二:耶!
Bobotz brother 2: Yea.
杰森:先生们.
Jason: Gentleman.
波波茨兄弟之二:噢!西维尔先生,是您办的这次彩票活动?
Bobotz brother 2: Oh, hi sir.Will you be conducting the raffle?
乔迪:彩票活动已经取消了,小鬼.
Jody: The raffle's cancelled, jerk bag.
波波茨兄弟之一:不会吧?
Bobotz brother 1: What?
本:没错,取消了.
Ben: Yea.
杰森:等等!托德!
Jason: Hold it, Todd.Wait, Benny.
本,我看惩罚你最好的办法,
You know I think a better punishment for you might be to just go ahead
就是让抽彩票照常进行,快点跟你的车再见.
with this raffle and you can just say goodbye to your bike.
本:我不要,爸爸.
Ben: What?No, Dad.
杰森:你自己来开奖!看看,
Jason: As a matter of fact, you can pick the winning ticket, alright?
谁会中奖.
Come on, you'll make some kid very happy.
本:3号中奖.
Ben: And the winner is 3.
乔迪:我中奖了!我中奖了!!我中奖了!!!
Jody: I won!I won!I won!
波波茨兄弟之二:乔迪,要是胆敢碰那辆车一下,我们要你好看.
Bobotz brother 2: You're gonna get it Jody.
杰森:放肆!!你们要是胆敢威胁这位小姑娘,你们兄弟俩就玩完了.
Jason: Wait a minute now.We don't threaten young ladies here, Benny.
波波茨兄弟之一:嘿.我叫班尼.
Bobotz brother 1: Hey, I'm Benny.
波波茨兄弟之二:我是托德.
Bobotz brother 2: I'm Todd.
杰森:都给我滚蛋.
Jason: I don't care.Get out of here!
麦琪:杰森,得跟孩子们好好谈谈.
Maggie: Jason, we've got someone to talk to.
杰森:那当然,重点是迈克!
Jason: Oh, come on.You said you'd take Mike this time.
麦琪:不是迈克,开萝尔干的!
Maggie: It wasn't Mike.It was Carol.
杰森:开萝尔干的?
Jason: What?
迈克:就是她,你们想不到吧.
Mike: Yea, we're all pretty stunned.
麦琪:原来如此.
Maggie: Come on.
杰森:不会是开萝尔吧?开萝尔·西维尔?
Jason: Not our Carol.Carol Seaver?
麦琪:嗯,就是她.
Maggie: Yes.
本:嗨!乔迪,
Ben: Gee, Jody, I'm pretty glad you won the bike cause since we're best
很高兴是你中了彩,咱们俩是好朋友,我知道你一定会把自行车还我的.
friends and everything, I know you'll give it back.
乔迪:嗯,本,那当然.
Jody: Yea, Ben, right.
迈克:这下明白了吧!!我警告过你!!
Mike: Eh, I could've warned you about women.
本:以后再也不找开萝尔了.
Ben: I should've never gone to Carol.
迈克:没错,吃一堑,长一智.
Mike: Ah, you're learning.
本:因为你老是要我为你干这干那,我才去找她的.
Ben: I only did it because you were abusing me.
迈克:我都让你干什么了?
Mike: How?
本:打蜡!擦车!倒垃圾!擦皮鞋!!烫衣服!!
Ben: Waxing your car, doing your chores, shining your shoes, ironing your...
迈克:好了,好了,好了,好了,也许我也得从中好好学习一下.
Mike: Ok, ok.Maybe I've learned a lesson here, too.
本:什么?
Ben: What?
迈克:也许烫衣服是过分了一点.
Mike: Maybe the ironing was a little too much.
本:其实我还是比较喜欢烫衣服的.
Ben: I kind of liked the ironing.
迈克:这个改天再说.
Mike: Alright, we'll talk.
本:我的自行车怎么才能要回来呢.
Ben: How am I supposed to get my bike back from Jody?
迈克:本,我可是此中高手.
Mike: Well, Ben, I am fairly skilled in handling women.
本:你能帮我?
Ben: You'd help me?
迈克:当然,你是我老弟不是?
Mike: Of course, you're my brother.
本:说得对,谁还要Carol呢.
Ben: Yea, you're right.Who needs Carol?
迈克:其实开萝尔的主意还是很不错的,但是她没好好去干.
Mike: Yea, you know,
I think she was onto something with this raffle thing though.
She just didn't know how to make it work for her.
本:不解?!
Ben: I don't get it.
迈克:老弟,这你就不懂了.
Mike: Let me explain it to you, bro.
你看好的主意固然很重要,
See, although a good idea is important,
但更重要的是怎么样去做,
what really counts is what you do with it.
你得问问自己,人们追求的究竟是什么.
See, you got to ask yourself, what is it that everyone really wants?
麦琪:开萝尔,
Maggie: Well, Carol, we just hope doing kitchen duty for a month will
希望你打扫一个月的厨房能让你好好反省一下这件事.
teach you that it's wrong to run scams.
开萝尔:妈妈,这是第一次闯了祸被逮着,
Carol: Mom, for the first time in my life I messed up, got in trouble,
显然你们也对我施以严厉的惩罚.
and I'm getting severely punished.
杰森:那你还干嘛那么高兴?
Jason: Why do you sound so happy?
开萝尔:嗯!坦白说,这事干起来倒挺带劲的.
Carol: Well, frankly, I found the whole thing, I don't know, interesting.
杰森:你觉得带劲?
Jason: Interesting?
开萝尔:嗯,太刺激了.
Carol: Yea, kind of exciting.
麦琪:开萝尔,你居然说这话?!
Maggie: Carol, are you saying
开萝尔:策划,冒险,一步步去干.现在我才知道,迈克老是惹祸,原来这么有带劲刺激.
Carol: The planning, the danger, the execution, I guess I know now why Mike finds this delinquent behavior so delicious
杰森:看到没,迈克的追随者日渐增多……
Jason: You know, Mike has a real capacity to just...
麦琪:我知道,我知道.
Maggie: I know, I know.
杰森:本……
Jason: And Ben
麦琪:正在重蹈其辙.
Maggie: Is on his way.
杰森:如果开萝尔也紧随其后的话…….
Jason: So if we lose Carol, too
麦琪:那我们就落下风了.
杰森:看来我们得再生一个,而且要抓紧.
00:22:30,900
Maggie: We're outnumbered. Jason: We better have another baby quick.